Artúr Foden

3A Worthington House, Clancy Quay, Dublin 8, D08 DRW2, Ireland

Phone:(+353) 01 443 4590 | E-Mail: fodena@tcd.ie

Website: www.arturfoden.ie | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/art%C3%BArfoden/

GitHub: https://github.com/Arturius771?tab=repositories

I am an ambitious and a well-rounded IT professional with experience in large scale business and personal projects. I have a broad educational background covering arts, sciences, and computer science. In developing my career, I am passionate about increasing accessibility in the workplace. My design approach is to consider the user experience first in the final product.

Skills

Computer Science – I am knowledgeable in digital logic, computer programming, algorithms, data structures, and web technologies. I have experience with Java, C#, ABAP, Python, SQL, PHP, HTML/CSS/XML and Javascript, in Windows/Linux environments. I am skilled in testing, debugging, and application development. I am familiar with Agile and Scrum frameworks for project management.

Communication – I have excellent written and verbal English language skills. I can write precise and clear documentation and knowledge articles. My interpersonal and team skills are strong. **Innovation** – At work I was involved with our location's innovation project to drive creative thinking and adaptation to increase productivity in the workplace. In this role I gained a qualification in Design Thinking and managing events. I also faced the challenges of dealing with corporate inertia to help deal with the deeper issues facing innovation.

Programming Languages

Java, C++, C#/.NET Framework/ASP, Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL, ABAP **Tools**

Git/GitHub, Flask, React, Node.js, Trello, OpenStack, Solution Manager, Visual Studio Code, WordPress, Unity3D, Linux, Windows.

Software Projects

- Innovation Club, design thinking sessions on improving customer experience, SAP.
- Simulation of physical Solar-system, C#, Unity 2017.
- ImEnt, network analysis software, C#, Visual Studio 2019.
- IBAT BMI Calculator, Java, NetBeans IDE.
- Book/Library Class, Java, BlueJ.
- Erehwon Guest House CRUD Application, JavaScript/PHP/SQL, Visual Studio Code/MariaDB.
- AstraDB eCommerce DBaaS Application, Java/JavaScript, Visual Studio Code/AstraDB.
- Prototype Diary App, JavaScript, Visual Studio Code.

Website Projects

- Walton Hall Museum website, HTML/CSS, Visual Studio Code.
- Kellermen's Resort website, WordPress, group project.
- Personal website, JavaScript/PHP, Visual Studio Code.
- Phasmocrew.org website, HTML/CSS, Visual Studio Code.
- VoltIreland.ie website, WordPress.

Work Experience

November 2021-present [2022]

Google Developer Student Club Open University Team Member

June 2018-present [2022] Support Engineer, Solution Manager, Monitoring/Alerting

Design Thinking Coach

Innovation Ambassador, Ireland and UK, Product Support

[2019]

SAP, Dublin, Ireland.

This role involves debugging code, reviewing software configuration, and writing knowledge articles for Solution Manager and Focused Run, which are Application Lifecycle Management tools for SAP's SaaS ERP products.

March-April 2017 Volunteer

Specialisterne, Dublin and Galway.

In this role I was responsible for managing an exhibit that demonstrated the difficulties faced by people with autism. Clients were corporate institutions who wanted to learn about the possible benefits of integrating autistic people into the workplace.

Education

September 2020-present [2022] Computing and IT (Computer Science)

Open University, [Online].

Computer Science, Digital Logic Design, Object Oriented Programming, Web Development (Full Stack), Mathematics, Operating Systems, Databases, Digital Ethics, Data Analytics, Machine Learning/AI, User Experience, Binary, Hardware, Networking, Testing, Error Handling, Software Development (Full development life cycle), Cloud Computing.

September-November 2017 Diploma in Computer Programming (Java) [Distinction]

IBAT, Dublin.

Java, Object-Oriented Programming, GUI, Error Handling, Project Management, IDE Experience.

September 2012-September 2013 Foundation Course in Higher Education

Trinity Access Programmed

Trinity College, University of Dublin, Dublin 2.

History, Law, Philosophy, Political Science.

Interests

- Computers, Video Games, Programming (C#, Java), Game Development (Unity3D), Developing a personal website (HTML), Building Computers.
- Reading books (fiction, autobiographies), music, and movies & TV.
- Aviation, Sailing, Surfing and Swimming.

References

- Stephen Grainger: SAP, <u>stephen.grainger@sap.com</u> (+353 1 4717 047)
- Dylan McKenna: Character Reference, mckenndy@tcd.ie (+353 85 825 9080)